On the end of April at Nippon Budokan, All Japan Judo Tournament were held.
全日本柔道锦标赛于4月在日本武道馆举行。
This tournament is an open-weight one, where all players from light-weight to over 100kg compete with each other for the title of Japan's strongest Judo player.
这场比赛是无重量级的，其中有轻量级选手和超过100公斤的选手，互相争夺日本最强的柔道运动员称号。
Look at these powerful heavyweight players gathering here.
看看这些强大的重量级选手。
A remarkably lightweight player tries to contend for the title among them.
一个非常轻量级的参与者想试图争夺这个称号。
His name is Shohei Ono. He is 25 years old and a 73kg class judo player.
他的名字叫大野将平。他25岁，一个73公斤级柔道选手。
On August 2016 ,  at Rio 2016 summer games olympics
2016年8月，在2016年里约夏季奥运会
This is " the Beautiful Japan's Judo" , which Ono always sticks to and wants to show us.
这是“美丽的日本柔道”，大野始终坚持，并向我们展示。
He won by Ippon in 4 matches out of 5.
他用一本赢得了4场比赛的5分。
He made it!
他成功了！
He won the gold medal. As Japanese Men's Judo, this gold medal is for the first time in 2 summer games olympics.
他赢得了金牌。这是日本男子柔道在本次夏季奥运会的第一块金牌。
He did climbed up to the top, but he never stops where he is and tries to move forward.
他登上顶端，但他从来没有停止，并试图向前推进。
His next objective is All Japan Judo Tournament, which is an open-weight tournament as mentioned before.
他的下一个目标是全日本柔道锦标赛，如前所述，这是一个无重量级的比赛。
I want to exceed my 73kg weight class which is relatively small.
我想超出轻量的73公斤级。
I want to see how far I can go at All Japan, open-weight. I want to try myself there.
我想看看我能走多远，在全日本无重量级的比赛。我想试试自己在那里试试。
”Grab tightly then throw. No run”  He wants to beat big players for his straight forward Judo.
“紧紧抓住再扔。不要跑” 他想打败大个选手，向他的目标前进。
Small Ono takes the risk of getting injured and tries to challenge the objective which people might think as reckless.
大野有伤病的风险，并试图挑战被人们认为是胆大妄为的目标。
Day after day, he takes a look at his own technique by himself.
日复一日，他需要看看自己的技术。
He trains his whole body to the limit.
他训练让他的整个身体到了极限。
when I get tired, I want to show my spirit.
当我累了，我会表明我的勇气。
We have covered him closely until All Japan Judo Tournament. He is the guy who trusts his own straight-forward Judo.
我们先暂不看他在全日本柔道锦标赛的表现。他是一个相信自己“向前的柔道”的人。
"Whenever I fight fare and square"  Shohei Ono - JUDO
“不管什么时候我都会保持坚定的战斗” 大野将平 - 柔道
At Tenri, Nara Pref, Japan. February, 6 months have passed since Rio olympic.
在日本的天理，奈良县，里约热内卢奥运会已经过去了6个月。
Shohei Ono, 25 years old
大野将平，25岁
Good morning
早上好
Today is a heavy snow, isn't it?
今天下了一场大雪对吧？
He has already started training to his new objective after winning the gold medal.
他赢得金牌后，已经为了他的新目标开始训练。
Here is his old school, Tenri University.
这里是他天理大学的老同学。
Randori,  free practice in judo.
实战练习（乱取り），柔道自由练习。
7 minutes Randori, 10 sets.
7分钟实战练习，10组。
He does Randori intendedly with his junior in heavyweight class.
他在实战练习中，有意地与年轻重量级的人练习。
It is not easy for small player to fight against big player with grabbing tightly with both hands.
对于小选手对抗大个子，小选手很难用双手紧紧抓住。
If big player leans his heavyweight to Ono directly, he may get injured.
如果直接把大重量级选手跟大野练习，大野可能会受伤。
Ono, however, sticks to grab anyone tightly with both hands.
大野，然而，坚持用双手紧紧地抓住对手。
This is his favorite technique, Osoto-gari.
这是他最喜欢的技术，大外刈。
And here is another his favorite, Uchimata.
还有另外一个他最喜欢的，内股。
"Grab tightly with both hands then throw the opponent" , which is the traditional way of Japan's JUDO. Now he is challenging to the open-weight tournament with this traditional way.
“用双手紧紧地抓住再摔对手”，这是日本柔道的传统方式。现在，他用这种传统方法挑战无重量级锦标赛。
No one but Ono as gold medalist has a special thought behind his new objective.
大野作为金牌得主，背后有他一个特别的新目标。
Ono did climb up to the top at Rio.
大野确实爬上了里约奥运会的顶部。
Yeah!!
是啊！
In delightful moment, he was trying to find what to do next.
在激动的时刻，他正在试图找到下一步目标。
Japanese people want him to win the gold medal in a row at 2020 Tokyo Olympic.
日本人希望他在2020东京奥运会赢得金牌。
He knows there is no improvement with keep doing the same as always.
他知道如果继续按照往常一样做的话没有提高。
He came to the conclusion. The conclusion is to partcipate the open-weight tournament. He has chosen not to do that until Olympic game ends.
他做出决定。在（里约）奥运会结束后参与无重量级锦标赛。
From the point of view In 73kg class,   well...   I became a champion at this moment.
从在73公斤级，嗯......我成了在这一刻冠军。
Now I feel the existence inside of me, the one is not satisfied a bit.
现在我觉得内心的我，他不单单只满足了这一点。
We have an old JUDO saying, "Ju yoku Go wo seisu, which means softness controls hardness.
我们有一个柔道谚语，“柔よく剛を制す”，这意味着以柔克刚。
I think one of the best part of JUDO is to see small guy controls and throws big guys with his skills.
我觉得柔道最精彩的部分之一就是看小选手，并用他的技能去克制大选手。
Commonly big player can win. I want to challenge that difficulty.
（无重量级比赛中）一般大选手选手赢。但我想挑战。
I want to oppose the common. That is the enough reason why I am Shohei Ono.
我想不走寻常。这是我大野将平。
At here,  All Japan Judo Tournament, several weight class players including who won the regional tournament compete altogether in one open-weight division.
在这里，全日本柔道锦标赛，这些重量级选手，其中一些人赢得无重量级的区域赛。
Successive Champions are mostly from heavyweight class.
历届冠军大多来自重量级选手。
Yasuhiro Yamashita , who won the championship for 9 times in a row from 1977 to 1985
山下泰裕，在1977至1985年9次连续赢得了冠军
Kosei Inoue , who won the championship for 3 times in a row from 2001 to 2003
井上康生，2001至2003年续3次连续赢得了总冠军
we could see the player in lightweight once in several years.  He is Jumpei Morishita , who was the champion in  66kg class of world championship Judo.
在几年前有轻量级选手赢一次。他叫森下純平，66公斤级世锦赛柔道冠军。
Even the world champion in his weight class could be beaten by regional heavyweight player at ease.
即使是重量级世界冠军也可能会被区域重量级选手轻松击败。
Toshihiko Koga, a gold medalist in 71kg at Barcelona Olympic. He fought with over 100kg players and advanced to the final at this tournament in 1990.
古賀稔彦，巴塞罗那奥运会71公斤级金牌得主。他跟超过100公斤的选手比赛，在1990年无重量级锦标赛晋级到决赛。
He moved around well. He would not let them grab tightly.
他移动好，但对手不会让他紧紧地抓住。
Once he grab, he tried to throw immediately. If failed, he move away immediately.
当他抓住，他试图马上摔出。如果失败了，他立刻移动出来。
Judge.  White flag, Koga.
裁判。白旗，古贺。
He used his advantage very well as small player to fight against big players.
他很好地离用自己小选手的优势为跟大个子选手对抗。
3 years ago, Ono fought in a different way at this tournament.
3年前，大野以另一种的方式在比赛中对抗。
He dared to fight in his own way as always , grab tightly with both hands and throw. He faced to heavyweight players with this way at this tournament.
他一如既往用自己的方式作战，用双手紧紧地抛投。在本次比赛中他面对重量级的选手。
Uchimata
内股
Osoto-gari
大外刈
He has noticed he is not strong enough to fight against the heavy guys in this way.
他意识到自己还不足够强大跟这位沉重的对手对抗。
I ,of course, thought I could go further in a clever way. As a small player, I could use a so- called small players advantage or way of judo.
我会以为自己更好的方式走得更远。作为一个小选手，可以利用作为小选手的优势和柔道的技巧。
But!  That's not it. I will do my own way of Judo.
但！不是仅仅是这，我会贯通自己柔道方式。
No run, fight straightforward with brave. If I did this, I might be able to see the things from the different point of view after this.
不逃避，勇敢直白面对。如果这样做，也许能看到在此之后不一样的风景。
at March in Osaka
三月 大阪
How could my techinques work for bigger players?
怎么才能跟自己更强壮的选手比赛呢？
Ono decided to train in the other gym for 2 days.
大野决定在其它健身房训练2天。
Kenichi Uezumi, the coach at Tokai University says "Oh Hi. We are glad to train with you guys."
上水研一朗教练 东海大学：“哦，你好。我们很高兴能与你们一起训练。”
Ono says "Thank you for having us here."
大野：“请多多关照。”
Tokai Univ, is the college Judo Champion team.
东海大学，是高校柔道冠军。
It is a great chance to train with lots of players who are not as usual.
跟许多不同往常风格的选手训练，这是一个很好的机会。
Randori starts.
实战练习开始。
This player is the 2nd place in 100kg class at All Japan Junior Tournament
这名选手是全日本青少年比赛100公斤级的第二名
The opponent is heavier in 3 weight classes, a university student in 100kg class.
对手是较重的3个重量等级，是一位100公斤级的大学生。
Ono wants to grab each other tightly.
大野想紧紧地抓住对方。
Oosoto-gari
大外刈
Ono did throw him in a moment.
大野那一瞬间摔倒了他。
No one in Japan but Ono can fight well against big players with grabbing like this  as a lightweight player.
在日本，没有人可以像77公斤级轻量级选手大野这样，抓住对大重量选手对抗。
First, almost all players are thrown by Ono. They are surprised at the unexpected power of Ono's technique.
首先，几乎所有的选手都被大野抛出。他们对大野的技术感到意外。
The heavier the player is, the harder Ono throw them.
对方越重，大野就越难摔。
This player is 2nd place at Tokyo region and he will participate to All Japan Judo Tournament.
这名选手是在东京地区的第2位，他将参加全日本柔道锦标赛。
Nearly 60kg gap in their body weight is held between these 2 players.
正在比赛的这两个选手之间体重差距几乎60kg。
Even Ono cannot throw him at ease.
大野怎么都不能将他摔倒。
Even though, Ono dragged him around and throw him at last.
即便如此，大野上拖动他，最后把他摔倒。
This coach who raised many world judo champions was very impressed by Ono.
这个教练带出了很多世界柔道冠军，他对大野印象非常深刻。
It is very risky to grab with 2 hands and fight in front. It really is.
在前面并对抗用两手抓住。（对于轻量级选手来说）这真的是非常有风险的。
We cannot do this without real strength.
没有真正的实力，不能做到这一点。
5 mins Randori, 20 sets for 2 days.
5分钟实战练习，2天20组。
Ono did throw almost all players here and never been thrown by them.
大野摔倒了在这里在几乎所有的选手，而且大野都没有被他们摔倒过一次。
Nevertheless, Ono was not satisfied enough.
不过，大野不够满意。
You did train well enough, didn't you?
你训练已经做得很好了，不是吗？
No no. I have never trained well enough.
不，不。我受的训练还不够好。
If I am not tired, I want to train with much bigger players though.
如果我不累，我想跟更重的选手训练。
OK.  I'd better get going.
好。我先走了。
Here's the cover that shows Ono fight in fair and square whenever he do judo.
这是小野在场上进行柔道比赛的图片。
This cover is the magazine in France
这是法国的柔道杂志
Who is the guy thrown by Ono?
被大野摔倒的家伙是谁？
Teddy Riner,  2 times in a row Olympic gold medalist in +100kg class.
泰迪·瑞纳，100公斤级奥运会的2连霸金牌得主。
His height is  2.04 m (6 ft 8 in) and his weight is 140 kg (310 lb)
他的身高2.04米（6英尺8英寸）。他的重量为140公斤（310磅）
Everytime Ono participates in Judo Camp,  he always tries to fight with Riner, who is twice as heavy, to see if his techniques are worked or not.
每当大野在柔道训练营训练，他总是试图与他两倍重的瑞纳比赛，看看他自己技术没有作用。
I was thrown by Ono cos his technique is absolutely wonderful.  hahaha.
我被大野的技术摔倒是非常精彩的。哈哈哈。
The tremendousness and the beaty among his technique express JUDO itself. I love to see his JUDO very much.
他豪快精彩的技术阐释着柔道的精神本身，我喜欢看他这样的柔道。
Why can Ono in 77kg class throw bigger players?
为什么77公斤级的大野可以摔倒比他更重的选手？
We are closing in on the secret behind that.
我们正在研究背后的秘密。
First, we are going to check out his muscles.
首先，我们看看他的肌肉。
This reminds me of Super Saiyan in Dragon Ball.
想起了龙珠里超级赛亚人。
Now we are checking his body fat and lean body mass with this special equipment.
现在，我们用这个特殊的设备检查他的体脂肪率和除脂肪体重。
OK done with measuring, so pls come out.
好了，测量完成，请出来。
Just a second till we get the result.
结果等一下出来，请稍等一下。
The result says your body fat is 4.5%. Is this same as always?
结果显示你体内的脂肪为4.5％。这是跟往常一样吗？
I don't know exactly. I thought my body fat is around 10%.
事实上我不太清楚。我想我的身体脂肪应该是10％左右。
Oh really?
真的吗？
This time with this equipment, your body fat is 4.5% and lean body mass is 75.144kg.
这一次，这个设备，你体脂肪率为4.5％，除脂肪体重是75.144千克。
Nevertheless he is not at the period of losing weight at this moment, his body fat is as same as the top body builder's one.
不过他没有在这时段减肥，他的身体脂肪和顶级健美运动员一样的程度。
We measured the thickness of muscles one by one to see which muscles are developed well.
我们一个一个地测量肌肉的厚度，看哪个肌肉发达。
Your muscle is developed very well.
你的肌肉发育得很好。
I can see the pump.
我可以看到泵样器官。
Yes pumped
是的，泵样器官
By the result, even though he is not big, his muscles are developed to the limit of his body frame.
从该结果，尽管他并不很壮大，但他的肌肉发达到了身体的极限。
Takanori Ishii, Prof. in Ryoutokuji Univ. says His class is 77kg class but he has as same muscle amounts as 81 to 90 kg class player have.
了德寺大学的石井孝法教授说，他是77公斤级，但他有81到90公斤级的选手同样的肌肉量。
His whole body muscles are big. Moreover, the parts of muscles for using his techniques at judo are especially developed.
他全身的肌肉都大。此外，他在柔道方面运用技巧的肌肉特别发达。
Red parts are the places where are more developed than the muscles of same weight class players.
红色是比相同重量等级运动员的肌肉更发达的部分。
Erector spinae muscles, which works for standing straight at the grappling with each other.
竖脊肌，它用于在相互摔斗中保持站立。
The right Abdominal external oblique muscles
右腹部外斜肌
And right hamstring
还有，右大腿肌
These three parts are the key muscles of Ono's Judo.
这三个部分是大野柔道的主要肌肉。
The right Abdominal external oblique muscles are used when Ono tries to stay still or control the opponent in a grappling postion.
右腹外斜肌可以让大野保持稳住静止，或正位控制对手。
The right hamstring is for the kick of Uchimata or Osoto-gari to jump them up or turn them down.
右大腿肌的作用于用大外刈或者是内股的踢跳摔倒对方。
To win Judo in limited weight, technique, style and  strength must be balanced at the high level.
为了在有限的重量，技术，风格和实力胜利，柔道必须在高层次进行平衡。
I think his body is balanced well to the limit.
我认为他的身体平衡到了极限。
And further measurement shows us that Ono has his original skills to compete with big guys.
进一步的测量显示，大野有着与大选手竞争的独到技能。
Capturing the markers on Ono's body, we can see the directions of techniques and the change of speed.
捕获的大野身上的标志，我们可以看到做动作时方向和速度的变化。
We focused on the momentums of his rotating.
注意于他旋转的势头。
We did analyze how fast the both of Ono and the partner who is thrown rotates.
看看大野和他的搭档旋转的速度有多快。
Ono spins his body very widely with his leg raised before starting Uchimata.
当大野做內股的动作之前，身体和腿的移动幅度很大。
Once Ono throws by Uchimata, the partner is thrown rapidly with a big circular motion.
当大野使用內股，对手就马上大圈被抛出。
These graphs indicates the momentums. Blue is for Ono, Red is for the partner thrown.
这些图表显示动量。蓝色是大野，红色是抛出的对手。
Ono is swinging his left leg widely to rotate and Blue line is going up. We can see the momentum is raised.
大野把他的左腿摆的幅度很大，旋转起来，蓝线在上升。我们可以看到势头（动量）正在增强。
As soon as Ono throw, the partner's Red line is rising suddenly.
当大野一摔，对方的红线突然上升。。
This tells us that the huge momentum of Ono was transmitted to the partner's body in a second and the partner was thrown at an incredible rate.
这告诉我们，大野的巨大动量在一秒钟内传递给对手，使对手以很快的速度被摔出。
In comparison to a top ranked judo player in 81kg class which one class heavier,
跟一位比较顶尖的81公斤级较重的柔道选手比较，
There is a remarkable difference between them. That is the Red line which indicates the momentum of body thrown.
两者之间存在显着差异。红线表示投掷身体的动量。
Ono is in one class lighter, but he can throw more explosively than the 88kg guy.
虽然大野是较轻，但他可以抛出时比88公斤级选手更有爆发力。
First, he produces the momentum by rotating the body with swinging his left leg widely.
首先，他通过摆动左腿来旋转身体来产生动力。
Second, he transmits the momentum to the opponent with great precision.
其次，他以极高的精准度向对手传递动量。
By doing these 2 complicating movements precisely, small Ono creates the explosive power.
通过精确地完成这2个复杂的动作，大野有了大爆炸力。
Prof. Ishii says" In real matches, Ono will try to make bigger momentum within his body and try to transmit it to the opponent."
石井教授说：“在真正的比赛中，会使更大的动量并传递给对方。”
Considering this Ono's momentum in lab, I definitely can tell that Ono can create extremely huge power in real matches and the opponents try no to be thrown but they can't stand up. Literally, they are blown away."
根据大野在实验室里的冲力，我可以肯定地说，大野可以在真正比赛中使出巨大力量，即使对手想防御，他们也站不稳。真像被被吹倒了一样。”
Here are the trainings he does to maximize the power of techniques.
这是他为最大限度发挥技术力量所做的训练。
At here, pedal harder. Harder, you can do it more!!  Much harder! Good, you did it.
在这里，用力踩踏板。再努力，你可以做得更多！更努力！很好，你做到了。
He trains like these everyday. This is the reason why Ono can throw heavyweight players
他每天都这样训练。这就是为什么大野可以投重量级选手的原因
Ono started Judo at 7 years old.
大野在7岁开始柔道。
2 years elder brother influenced him.
因为大两岁的哥哥对他的影响。
Here is the man who taught Ono to fight fare and square.
这是教大野在赛场上比赛的人。
His name is Haruya Mochida. He is Ono's former teacher in junior and senior high school.
他叫持田治也。他是大野中学高校时期的教练。
This brings back memories.
真让人怀念。
Ono did learn and train at the boarding school, Kodogakusha, where 2 gold medalists Koga and Yoshida learn too.
大野学习并且寄宿学校-讲道学舍，这里出了其中2位金牌得主古贺和吉田。
But first, Ono was a normal and discreet player.
但首先，大野是一个正常和谨慎的选手。
Well  he was bit thin. That was what I thought.
嗯，我觉得他是有点瘦。
In fact, he was probably second or third to last when entering exam match.
事实上，他在参加考试时可能是第二名或第三名
Osoto-gari is the first technique he taught to Ono. To do Osoto-gari,  we need to grab the opponent tightly with both hands.
大外刈是他教给大野第一个技发。要做到大外刈，需要用双手紧紧地抓住对手。
Carelessly doing Osoto-gari, you never throw them or even they would have a chance to throw you back.
漫不经心地做大外刈，你不仅不会摔倒对方，他们反而有机会摔倒你。
So we must step forward without fear.
因此，我们必须挺身而出，无所畏惧。
Mochida told Ono again and again " Step forward. Push forward. Do not think if opponent would throw you back or not."
持田一再告诉大野“向前一步。推进。不要考虑如果对手会把你摔倒。”
He told me only one thing "Push forward intently. Once the opponent step back, throw him by  Osoto-gari." He kept saying to me again and again.
他告诉我：“向前推进。一旦对手退一步，通过大外刈把他摔倒”。他一次又一次地对我说。
I think the moment was my turning point of Judo.
我认为这是我练柔道的转折点。
As Ono tried to throw big players by Osoto-gari again and again even though he was thrown back many times,  his style " grab well and throw" was established.
当大野不断地用大外刈摔倒大对手，即使他自己也被投倒多次，慢慢形成他的“抢位后摔”的风格。
He believes the way he trusts once. He never quit till it accomplished.
他一旦想做一件事的话就会坚信到底。直到完成之前不会放弃。
He did not care how many times he was thrown back. He ain't pessimistic. He did not think that this technique is not good for him.
他不在乎被摔了多少次。他不悲观。他不会去先想这个技术好不好。
He got to the place where he believes " OK, I will do the way. This is my style."
（练习时）到了他认为的点，就会确定自己的风格。”
After entering Tenri Univ, he did not quit polishing the technique and kept the teaching of Mochida.
进入天理大学后，他并没有停止柔道技术，继续保持持田的教学训练。
When he was 4th year student in the university, he won the gold medal at World Judo tournament 2013.
当他4年的大学期间，他赢得了2013世界柔道锦标赛的金牌。
His style of Judo " grab well and throw" was about to be completed.
他的“抢位后摔”柔道风格差不多形成。
I have trained so many years till I could say this technique is my favorite one.
我训练了这么多年，目前为止有自己的得意技术。
Because of this, if there is a genius, of course I am not, even the genius never could make this happen in just one day. He or she might also need time to make one thing good enough. So I need more time.
即使是天才永远无法做到在短短的一天做到。（所以我需要更多的时间训练）
March, Osaka
三月，大阪
2 months out from All Japan Judo Tournament
离全日本柔道锦标赛前2个月
He visited the person who he wanted to meet before.
他拜访了他想认识的人
Here is a training camp for spring sumo wrestling tournament of Isegahama Sumo Gym.
这是伊勢ケ濱部屋相扑体育馆春季比赛训练营。
Good morning!!
早上好！！
Good morning!
早上好！
His name is Harumafuji. He is from Mongolia and one of 4 Yokozuna,  Grand Champions of Sumo wrestling.
他的名字是日馬富士。他来自蒙古，4个横纲之一，相扑大冠军。。(横纲：日本相扑选手资格的最高级，同时期在役的横纲通常不会超过四个)
Sumo wrestling is open-weight martial art.
相扑是无重量级的武术。
Among the top-division wrestlers, he is one of the lightest wrestlers.
在顶级摔跤手中，他是最轻的摔跤手之一。
He did climb to the top of Sumo wrestling world by fighting fare and square against bigger Sumo wrestlers.
他跟大的相扑选手相扑搏斗，登上了相扑世界的顶峰。
How did he reach the highest place?
他是如何做到这些？
Ono realized Harumafuji has special movements which compensate his small body.
首先，小野注意到日馬富士有用特别的移动来弥补身体的不足。
I am very impressed by your speed of the initial charge. It is very different from other wrestlers.
你最初的启动速度给我留下了很深的印象。其他摔跤运动员有很大的不同。（非常快）
Everyday I do train myself with checking my movement one by one.
一个一个地检查自己的训练动作。
Ono asked Harumafuji " What is the key when you fight with big guys?"
大野问日馬富士：“当你与大选手比赛，秘诀是什么？”
As you know, there is an old saying in Judo " Shin, Gi, Tai, or Mind, Skill and Body"
如你所知，柔道有“心技体”
We do have the same in Sumo " Mind, Skill and Body"
相扑一样有“心技体”
I also think Mind is the first key.
我觉得“心”是第一个关键
There are many injuries all over my body right now. but I can keep wrestling with everyone's supports. It makes me strong.
到大家的支持（让我坚强），最近在“心”里学习到相扑
Truly now I am supported by so many people.
诚然，受到这么多人的支持。
Mind exceeds Skill and Body.
心的境界比技能和身体更重要。
That is the answer of Harumafuji.
这就是日馬富士的答案。
I am trying to be strong at heart or mind. So I never think that I am light.
我尝试在心理或精神得到增强。我从来不认为自己厉害。
This is all.
这就是全部。
Mind is the key. Mind compensates Skill and Body. If I believe I have power enough to beat other, I have already for sure.
心是关键。心可以让技术和身体得到补偿。如果我相信自己有能力击败对手，就胜券在握了
To challenge with Mind makes me stronger than bigger players.
用心去比赛让我比大选手更强大
Thank you very much for having me.
非常感谢您邀请我。
Ono made up his mind.
大野心里有底了。
OK see you again.
好的，再见。
see you again.
再见。
"Pleasures of Judo to the people around the world" at the bottom of Feb, in Dusseldorf ,Germany
“把柔道的快乐传递给世界各地的人”。  二月底，德国的杜塞尔多夫
Ono teachs at his Judo class in oversea for the first time.
大野在海外第一次教柔道课。
As a coach, he teaches at various places.
作为一名教练，他在不同的地方任教。
I love it very much.
我很喜欢。
I really like today's training.
我真的很喜欢今天的训练。
It will be a great success that Kids in Germany want to do Judo again.
让德国的孩子想学习柔道，这将是一个巨大的成功。
April   at Tenri, Nara- Pref.
4月 天理，奈良县
2 weeks out from the tournament
离锦标赛还有两周
Ono has kept practicing to grab well and throw big players at Tenri University.
在天理大学大野一直保持练习摔大选手
He could not throw them at ease this day.
至少目前他还不能真正地摔倒大选手。
His juniors are going to know the timing of Ono's throwing while everyday Randori training.
大家都知道大野的日常实战训练的时间。
He, Kosei Inoue, the head coach of Japan's National Judo team, came to inspect here.
井上康生，日本的国家柔道队的主教练，来到这里观察。
After the training, Ono told Inoue the frustrating feelings inside.
培训结束后，大野告诉井上自己沮丧的心情。
Now I cannot throw at all.
目前我还不能摔倒他们（大选手）。
You did great enough, I think. You will change completely when you are in real matches.
你做的足够足够好了。当在真正的比赛，会有所改变。
I am struggling cos my juniors knows my techniques and the timing.
我在努力，因为知道他们想了解我的柔道练习情况。
Because he wants to do judo in his style, that reveals his techniques as well.
因为他想要做柔道在他的风格，也揭示了他的技术也是如此。
Even Ono can't throw big opponents easily who have already known Ono's techniques well.
即使大野不能把大对手轻易谁已经知道大野的技术很好。
He faced to the hard reality of small player.
他面对小选手的严酷现实。
Inoue says " I admit that small player is hard to fight in open-weight match."
井上说：“我承认，小选手很难在开放重量比赛打。”
He has the mind or soul to dare to challenge to the open-weight tournament. I think the mind will keep on making  Ono stronger and stronger.
他有心灵或灵魂敢于挑战的开放重量比赛。我觉得头脑会不断努力，使大野强。
He never fear defeats. He sticks to his belief.
他从不畏惧失败。他坚持自己的信念。
He made up his mind. He never lose his way.
他打定了主意。他永远不会失去他的方式。
All players are superior to me in this tournament. It is significant to do my Judo to heavyweight players.
所有玩家都优于我在本次比赛。这是显著做我的柔道重量级选手。
April 29th , All Japan Judo Tournament
4月29日，全日本柔道锦标赛
Many fans want to see Ono.
许多球迷希望看到大野。
In Judo we have a saying "small can control big by sklls."  so we are excited to see Ono.
在柔道，我们有一个说：“小可以控制sklls大。”因此，我们很高兴地看到大野。
I am a judo player but still weak. I want to see Ono's Judo and I want to learn from that to be strong.
我是一名柔道运动员，但仍然较弱。我希望看到大野柔道，我想从要学会坚强。
Ono is here at stadium now.
大野现在在这里的体育场。
He now checks the feeling of tatami mat. 3 years have passed since the last tournament he joined.
他现在检查榻榻米的感觉。自从参加了去年竞技场3年过去了。
Former teacher Mochida comes to encourage him.
以前的老师持田来鼓励他。
I am surprised at seeing so many people.
我在看到这么多的人感到惊讶。
All people came to see no one but you.
所有的人都来见任何人，但你。
No no no
不不不
I will do my best.
我会尽我所能。
There are 43 players at this tournament.
有43个的选手在这项赛事。
The average of weight is 109kg
重的平均值为109千克
Ono is the smallest and lightest player among them.
大野是其中最小，最轻的选手。
The first match has begun.
第一场比赛已经开始。
Ikeda in 100kg class and Matsumura, 142kg high school student fight here.
池田在百千克类和松村，142千克高中生打在这里。
Ono will fight the one who win this match.
大野会打谁赢得这场比赛的一个。
The winner is Ikeda.
获奖者是池田。
He did great job to 40kg heavier player.
他做了伟大的工作，40公斤重的选手。
Ono does not take any measures and does his own Judo.
大野不采取任何措施，并做他自己的柔道。
Here's the first match for Ono.
下面是大野第一场比赛。
The 2nd match Ono vs Ikeda
第二届比赛大野VS池田
Ono offends agressively from the start.
大野从一开始agressively冒犯。
Grab tightly!  Uchimata!!
紧紧抓住！ Uchimata！
Uchimata! Oh!
Uchimata！哦!
Ono is pushing forward very much.
大野正在推进非常多。
Osoto-gari
Osoto，木薯粉
And Seoi Nage.
而背负投。
He keeps throwing but fails.
他不断抛出，但失败。
Ikeda is now cautious about Ono's Throw. He tries to break Ono's left hand grab thoroughly.
池田现在是谨慎大野之遥。他试图彻底打破大野的左手抢。
He avoids fighting fare and square.
他避免了战斗车费和广场。
We have some experiences to train together. so I know he took measures.
我们有一些经验，一起训练。所以我知道他采取措施。
I cannot make him throw completely.
我不能让他彻底甩开。
5 mins match is over with no point of throw. The match is going into extra time.
5分钟比赛结束，没有点抛。比赛即将进入加时。
Ono kept attacking the 20kg heavier opponent.
大野保持攻击20千克较重的对手。
Gradually, he is getting tired. He is pushed back often at this moment.
渐渐地，他累了。他在这个时刻往往推后。
And yet he sticks to his belief.
但他坚持自己的信念。
I tried to grab precisely and throw precisely without any tricks.
我想正是为了抓住并精确抛出没有任何技巧。
Simply he pushes forward.
只要他向前推。
He tries to fight in front.
他试图在前面打。
Ippon
IPPON
9 mins 54 seconds
9分钟54秒
He was defeated by Ippon at last.
他被IPPON终于打败了。
Everyone applauses for the longest exciting match of today.
每个人都鼓掌为今天的最长的激动人心的比赛。
Ono's challenge for 3 months is now over.
现在Ono的3个月的挑战是结束了。
He is off to Mochida immediately after the match.
他是关闭的持田的比赛之后。
Now honestly I am wondering which is better, I do anything to win or stick to my style.
现在，说实话我不知道哪个更好，我做任何事情来取胜还是坚持我的风格。
You did great without playing cheap tricks.
你不玩花招便宜做得很好。
Cheap tricks might bring you a victory but I think you will be in trouble at next match cos you do not overcome the difficulties at all.
廉价把戏可能为你带来胜利，但我想你会遇到麻烦的下一场比赛，因为你根本就不克服困难。
Yes, I keep on going forward to the next.
是的，我一直在前进到下一个。
I am frustrated though.
我很沮丧，但。
We can start together again. We have time.
我们可以一起再次启动。我们有时间。
Either do I. I love to do.
要么我也是。我喜欢做的事。
Let's do over and over again.
让我们做了一遍又一遍。
We want to see what happens after experiencing that.
我们希望看到遇到后会发生什么。
Mochida praised what Ono did, which is to fight fare and square as same as before.
持田赞誉什么大野没有，这是打车费和广场为以前一样。
No matter how hard and painful, he never run away from them.
无论多么困难和痛苦，他从来没有跑远离他们。
After becoming Olympic champion, I am very proud of him with no fear but courage to be defeated.
成为奥运冠军后，我没有恐惧，但没有勇气被击败他感到骄傲。
He has confidence again through losing the match.
他再次通过输了这场比赛有信心。
being ready for losing is very tough option for me, but I did not run away from the difficulties.
在准备好输球对我来说是非常艰难的选择，但我没有逃避困难了。
I think I pushed forward well to do offensive Judo in this match.
我想我向前推好做柔道的进攻在这场比赛中。
I kept doing my own JUDO through the match without my heart break off.
我不停地通过比赛做我自己的柔道没有我的心脏折断。
I can learn from the today's loss. This loss  could become tomorrow's win.
我可以从今天的亏损，学习。这种损失可能成为明天的胜利。
I keep doing my best toward the 2020 Olymic.
我一直尽我所能对2020年Olymic。
You want to come back to this tournament again?
你想再次回到这个比赛？
People might think I am fool if I am here again. I know that really well indeed,  but I definitely come back and want to fight again at here.
人们可能会认为我是傻瓜，如果我再次在这里。我知道，真的很好的确，但我一定会回来，想在这里再次战斗。
I want to see everyone here excited to show them my own style of JUDO.
我想看看这里的每个人兴奋地告诉他们我自己的柔道风格。
Thank you for showing us your judo.
感谢您向我们展示你的柔道。
Thank you.
谢谢。
Ono is looking ahead to the future.
大野是展望未来。
That is to be a champion in a row at 2020 Tokyo Olympic.
这是要2020东京奥运会的一排冠军。
And more, That is to make another try to All Japan Judo Tournament.
而更多的，那就是让闯闯，以全日本柔道锦标赛。
Shohei Ono sticks to fight fare and square.
大野将平坚持打车费和广场。
"Whenever I fight fare and square"  Shohei Ono - JUDO
“每当我打车费和广场”大野将平 - 柔道